# **Jacob Nathanson**

## **Software Developer**







Brooklyn, NY jacobnath93@gmail.com 347.489.2611

## **Objective**

Caring, dependable, and detailed problem solver. After 3+ years in international education, I've pivoted to focus on scaling my impact through technology. I'm a patient and resilient problem solver with a growth mindset, positive attitude, and passion for strategic collaboration. I look forward to bringing my grit and dynamic skillset to bear for a fantastic team.

## **Skills**

HTML, CSS, SCSS, JavaScript, Java, Spring MVC, Spring Boot, React, Redux, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Node, Express, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Docker, and Github.

## **Projects**

**Scr-ai-be - (<u>live site</u> - github**) - I co-developed this product with two other engineers. This product uses Chat GPT 3.5 Turbo model to organize notes into concise clear points. It utilizes Java Spring Boot, OpenAI API JSON Web-Tokens, React, Tailwind CSS, and DaisyUI.

**FreeUp - (<u>live site - github)</u> - I** co-developed this project with another engineer, UX designer, and product manager. This web application helps New Yorkers find and give away free items that would otherwise be thrown out. It was built using PostgresSQL, Express, React, and Material UI.

**Descriptify** - <u>(live site</u> - <u>github</u>) - I designed and developed this web application. This product helps users create an Al-generated product description to help sell their items. The app utilizes OpenAl API, React, Redux Toolkit, Bootstrap, and Sass.

### **Education**

- Agile Software Development

Co.lab 2022

- Full-Stack Web & Mobile Development

NuCamp 2021-2022

- BA Psychology & Music

University of Michigan 2011-2015

## Work Experiences

**Dev10/** Associate Developer

APRIL 2023-JULY 2023 REMOTE, USA

- Chosen to work for highly selective, paid Java Full-Stack training less than 5% of applicants are hired
- Managed a team of developers to successfully deliver a fully functional MVP capstone project in two weeks.
- Lead study sessions to assist other associates in debugging and comprehending core material.

## Fisher's SuperKids/ ESL Teacher

AUGUST 2019- MARCH 2020 DA NANG, VIETNAM

- Taught English lessons for Vietnamese students ages 5 18, with classes averaging between 10-15 students.
- Provided weekly video-speaking challenges to review material and produce language in real-world scenarios.
- Used multimedia software and online activities to increase student engagement.

#### Fleisher's/ Wholesale Representative

SEPTEMBER 2016-NOVEMBER 2017 BROOKLYN, NEW YORK

- Managed over 80 wholesale accounts in New York City and Connecticut, connecting schools and restaurants with pasture-raised meat from local farms.
- Learned CRM systems to carefully manage a large influx of orders and strengthened organizational skills in order to prioritize and follow-up on unresolved tasks in a timely manner.